准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
上流章鱼哥
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
艺术馆
上流小姐
Lady Upturn
您能再临我们的画廊  令我倍感荣幸
Always a delight to have you back at our gallery
家里的艺术品我都看腻了
I'm bored by the art in my home
有没有什么新奇又有意思的
What do you have that's new and interesting?
我特地留了最新最上好的艺术品
Why, I've been saving our newest and finest pieces
供您欣赏
just for you
这幅作品是由我们一名新兴画家所作
This work is by one of our emerging artists
从哪里新兴的  石头底下吗
Where did they emerge from, under a rock?
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
上流小姐  我深感抱歉
Lady Upturn, I am so, so sorry
我不该向您展示那幅垃圾
I should never have shown you that dreck
放心
Never fear
下一样艺术保证让你激动不已
This next work is guaranteed to excite
裤头村第一舞剧团
Bikini Bottom's premier dance troupe
创作出了一出全新舞剧
has created a performance so new
就连他们自己都还不知道跳的什么
even they don't know what it is yet
跟着音乐节奏动来动去早就不新了
Moving in time to music is hardly new
我一样对此无感
This does nothing for me, either
这里肯定会有你喜欢的艺术品
Surely, there's something here you'll enjoy
恐怕并不会有
No, I'm afraid not
瑞吉吉尔德
Regigilled
我要散个步  来放空思绪
I need a walk to clear my mind
背着我走
Carry me
很好  女士
Very good, ma'am
我失败惨重
Alas, I have failed
真抱歉  女士
My apologies, madam
我应该马上带您远离这噪音
I shall remove your person from this cacophony at once
不用  瑞吉吉尔德
No, no, Regigilled
带我靠近点
Take me closer
如您所愿
As you wish
那边那位
You, there
就是你
Yes, you
我有权在这里吹竖笛
I'm allowed to play my clarinet here
这里可是自由的海洋
It's a free ocean, you know
我绝对不可能停
I'm not stopping
停
Stop?
我可不敢奢望
I wouldn't dream of it
那可是最有意思又前卫的音乐
That is the most interesting and avant-garde music
我多年以来闻所未闻
I have heard in years
太崇高了
It is sublime
你有赞助者吗
Do you have a patron?
我务必要赞助你
I simply must be yours
好好好  太好笑了
Yeah, yeah, very funny
想干嘛
What is this
藏了摄影机要拍个电视整人节目吗
one of those hidden-camera TV prank shows?
并非如此
Heavens, no
电视是最低级的艺术形式
Television is the lowest form of art
瑞吉吉尔德  给这位付钱
Regigilled, pay the man
你不能拿钱来收买我这种天才的灵魂
You can't just buy the soul of a raw talent like myself
小姐  你正好买到了个艺术家
Lady, you just bought yourself an artist
蟹堡王
废物们好啊
Hello, losers
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
你高兴个什么劲  章鱼哥先生
What's with all the joy, Mr. Squidward?
我现在是个带薪音乐家了
I'm a paid musician now
就你
You?
音乐家
Musician?
带薪
Paid?
随便你笑  反正是真的
Laugh all you want, but it's true
再也不用坐这只付最低工资的大牢了
I don't need this minimum-wage prison anymore
我辞职
I quit
章鱼哥的梦想终于要成真了
Squidward's dreams are finally coming true
欢迎光临你的新家  章鱼哥先生
Welcome to your new home, Mr. Tentacles
天啊  不可思议
Oh, my, it's incredible
但你又要住哪
But where are you going to live?
整栋豪宅都是我的
The mansion is mine
你只能住一间小房间
You just get one tiny room
天啊
Oh, my
我等不及要炫耀你
I cannot wait to show you off
给那些引领时尚的富豪朋友看了
to my wealthy, taste-making friends
最好马上开始作曲
so you better get writing
遵命  女士
Yes, ma'am, ma'am
再见  你这个天才
Toodle-oo, you genius, you
鲈多芬
鳊姆斯
龙虾拉斯
[ 贝多芬              勃拉姆斯                 李伯拉斯
德国音乐家         德国作曲家           美国钢琴家 ]
上流百货
没错
正在营业
给我让开  苦力
Out of my way, peon
真抱歉  大人
So sorry, my lord
章鱼哥
Squidward
你真是  非常自信
That was very, uh, confident of you
没错
Yes
成为艺术家就需要有艺术家的气质
Being an artist
requires having an artist's temperament
你这蠢材
you boob
干什么磨蹭这么久
What took you so long?
我只是过来邀请你们两位
Now, then, I'm only here to invite you both
前来观赏我的盛大首秀音乐会
to my big debut concert
见证我在裤头村最宏伟的舞台重生吧
Witness my rebirth
on the grandest stage in Bikini Bottom
前提是你们有假放
if you can get the time off
他不知怎么的
Somehow, he's even
比以前上班时还要讨厌
more annoying now than when he worked here
等等  蟹老板
Wait, Mr. Krabs
章鱼哥之所以会这么讨厌
Squidward is just being insufferable
是因为他的梦想都要成真了
because his dreams are coming true
一定要过去支持他
We have to go and support him
我们可是他朋友
We're his friends
朋友这俩字言过其实了  不过算了
Well, "friends" is a strong word, but fine
裤头村
著名剧院
今晚  章鱼哥
你好啊  章鱼哥
Hiya, Squidward
我跟蟹老板想来
Mr. Krabs and I just wanted to
在你上场前祝你好运
wish you luck before your big show
好运
Luck?
别傻了
Don't be stupid
我可是世上最伟大的音乐家
I'm the greatest musician who ever lived
这可是富豪杂志说的
Rich people say so
富豪杂志
世上最伟大的音乐家
钱确实有理
Can't argue with money
去找你们的位子吧
Now, go find your seats
我现在得准备上台
I'm in the middle of my pre-show ritual
可不能被打扰到
and I don't want to be bothered
晚上好  各位音乐爱好者
Good evening, music lovers
想必各位跟我一样  已经厌倦了
Like me, I'm sure you are tired of
老一套把戏奏出的老一套音符
the same old notes being played the same old ways
请各位放心
Well, fear not
今晚  你们终将听到全新的音乐
Tonight you will finally hear something new
今晚  为你们隆重介绍
Tonight I present to you
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward Tentacles
忘却你们的婚礼
Forget your wedding
忘却你们第一个子女的诞生
Forget the birth of your first child
今晚必将是
This is going to be
你们这辈子最美好的夜晚
the greatest night of your lives
多么动听啊  医生
Isn't it dazzling, Doctor?
没错
Yes
不好意思  上流小姐
Pardon me, Lady Upturn
我是否可以
May I?
当然了  鱼伯格医生
Of course, Dr. Fishberg
上流小姐  有只水母堵住了你耳朵
Lady Upturn, there's a jellyfish blocking your ears
天啊
Oh, goodness
一定是我在水母田散步时就蜇上去了
It must have gotten stuck up there
during my walk through Jellyfish Fields
他真实的音乐水平就这样吗
Is that what he really sounds like?
这音乐太难听了
This music is terrible
没错
Indeed
水母的嗡嗡声一定是改变了噪音
The jellyfish's buzzing must have altered the noise
所以你才会觉得好听
to be more pleasurable for you
不许再吵了
Stop that racket
住口
Stop it
你竟敢打断我
How dare you interrupt m--
我有话要向大家坦白
I have a confession to make
有只水母堵住了我的耳朵
A jellyfish was obstructing my ears
因此我并没有真正听到这骗子的音乐
so I hadn't truly heard this fraud's music
既然我已经听到了
And now that I have
那就冒犯到我了
I am offended
为弥补这糟糕演奏给各位带来的伤害
To make up for this abysmal performance
我想邀请各位回到我家
I would like to invite you all back to my home
体验真正的音乐
to experience real music
演奏者是我最新的艺术家
by my newest artiste
音乐大师派大星
Maestro Patrick Star
什么
What?
蛋黄酱
再来
Encore
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squidward
我们还想听
We want more
你们是认真的吗
Do you really mean it?
那当然了
Of course
我们有水母
We've got jellyfish
我就知足吧
I'll take what I can get
好耶
Yeah
加油  章鱼哥
Come on, Squidward
天外来章
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村新闻
最新消息  新证据表明
This just in: New evidence that
不明飞行物已秘密造访
unidentified flying objects
have been secretly visiting
裤头村长达数年
Bikini Bottom for years
上将
General
这些照片与视频造假的概率有多大
what are the chances that these photos
and videos are just a hoax?
99.99999%
情况就是这样
There you have it--
真凭实据表明
conclusive proof
飞碟有0.00001%的概率是真的
that there is a 0.00001% chance UFOs are real
所以说飞碟的证据可能无处不在
That means there could be evidence of UFOs anywhere
一起去找吧
Let's go find some
外星人快来
Here, alien
外星人
Alien
都已经大半夜了
It's the middle of the night
你们两个白痴在干什么
What are you two idiots doing?
我们找到了外星人怪圈
We found an alien crop circle
之所以有怪圈
It's only a crop circle
完全是因为你们乱踩我秋海棠
because you're stomping on my begonias
好吧
Okay
没错  就我们踩的
Yeah, that is us
我们在找外星人和飞碟
We're hunting space aliens and UFOs
根本就没有外星人跟飞碟
Space aliens and UFOs do not exist
给我去睡觉
Go to sleep
好
Okay
你们想看外星人是吗
You want to see space aliens?
那就给你们看外星人
I'll show you space aliens
这东西很有可能就是飞碟
This could definitely be a UFO
真的是飞碟
A real UFO
第一类接触
First contact
好星际
Intergalactic
好太空
Spacey
好宇宙
Cosmic
我们刚被个飞碟给撞了
We just got hit by a flying saucer
好耶
Yeah
酷
Cool
你们好  地球生物
Greetings, earthlings
是真的外星人
A r-r-real space alien
你好啊  先生
Greetings, sir
是我扮的  你们俩戴锡纸的白痴
It's me, you tinfoil twits
一直都是我
It was all me
根本就没有外星人
Space aliens don't exist
明白吗
Got it?
谢谢  章鱼哥
Thank you, Squidward
我们现在能明白自己有多傻了
We can see now how silly we really were
有了
I know
改扮超级英雄吧
Let's play superheroes instead
好啊
Yeah
起码超级英雄确实是真的
At least we know they're real
白痴
Idiots
总算找到了
At last
我们远古水下祖先存在的证据
evidence of our ancient aquatic ancestors
一定要把文物带回飞船
We must take the artifact back to the ship
我们会发大财
We'll be rich
发个大财
Rich, I say
早跟你们俩说了  根本没有外星人
I told you two, space aliens don't exist
快滚开
Go away
不好了
Oh, no
文物被寄生虫寄生了
The artifact is infested with a parasite
必须先把它消杀了才可以出发
We must eradicate it before our departure
我告诉你  这东西可难搞了
I'm telling you, it's always something
谁
Who--
谁啊
who's there?
我的洞
My holes
感谢海神王  我还有阅读眼
Thank Neptune I have my readers
老练的头脑
海绵宝宝跟派大星是走火入魔了吗
Have SpongeBob and Patrick gone cuckoo?
你们
You
海绵宝宝还有派大星
SpongeBob and Patrick
把你们这破面具摘了
take off those stupid masks
我知道是你们
I know it's you
住手
Stop it
你快伤到我了
You're hurting me
求救
Mayday
我们需要支援
We need backup
加入蟹堡王团队
你们两个在里面能不能闭嘴
Will you two shut up in there?
我还想把你们脑袋给
I'm trying to get your heads--
摘了
off?
那俩白痴还真是对的
Those nimrods were right
真的有外星人
Aliens are real
海绵宝宝  放我进去
SpongeBob, let me in
你说得对
You were right
转告派大星  你说得对
Tell Patrick you were right
成功
Success
害虫撤离了
The vermin has evacuated
来把文物带上飞船
Let's take the artifact to our ship
免得那只可怕臭虫又回来了
before that horrible stinkbug comes back
别
No
等等
Wait
别走别走别走
Wait, wait, wait
所以我就说  这就给你见识牵引光束
So I says, I'll show you a tractor beam
这里到底谁管事
All right, who's in charge here?
我要跟经理说话
I want to speak to the manager
经理
Manager?
带我去找你们的领导
Take me to your leader
那叫指导
That would be our supervisor
他办公室就在走廊里面
His office is down this hall
只要先左转再右转
You just make a left then a right
别跟他说话
Don't talk to him
他就是我们消杀的害虫
He is the vermin we eradicated
看来有谁消杀课挂科了
Looks like somebody failed eradication class
闭嘴
Zip it
我是你俩的上级
I outrank you both
我要你们把我家从哪找来就放回哪去
I want you to put my home back where you found it
能不能往前靠近点
Could you step forward?
我听不清
I'm hard of hearing
好
Sure
还有一件事
And another thing
你们干什么要来地球
What's the big idea of coming to my planet
就在我家庭院直接拐走我家房子
and taking my house out of my yard
就因为它样子就像你们的呆头吗
just because it looked like your stupid head?
会讲话的害虫危害最大了
Talking vermin are the worst kind
我说得对吧
Am I right?
为了稍微弥补一点损失
Just so it's not a total loss
建议咱们做点检查  来给它探测一下
I say we run some tests and do a probe
万岁
Hooray
我们要探测了
We're doing a probe
探测
Probe
Probe?
X光
X-ray
虽然头盖骨很大
Despite the large cranium
但大脑的尺寸似乎低于平均水平
the brain seems below average size
高血压
High blood pressure
最好小心一下脾气
Better watch that temper
转动脖子
Rotate neck
往鼻子塞水管
Nose hose
存储空间了不起
Impressive storage space
现在来做最有趣的部分
Now for the fun part
自由了
Freedom
爸爸
Daddy
不要
No
拜托不要探测我
Please don't probe me
这项探测要问的是
In this probe, I will be asking you
有关你童年的尴尬问题
embarrassing questions about your childhood
我应该确实不擅长交友
Well, I guess I did have trouble making friends
发泄很多被压抑的记忆之后
然后三岁时  我说
Then when I was three, I said
妈咪  早告诉过你了
"Mumsy, I told you
我不喜欢海草汁
I don't like kelp juice"
她就说  别管我叫妈咪
And she said, "Well, I don't like being called Mumsy"
然后
And then--
够了
Enough
滚吧  害虫
Good riddance, vermin
笨文物你自己留着吧
Keep your dumb, old artifact
你妈的故事也自己憋着吧
And you can keep your mother stories too
天啊
Oy vey
章鱼哥  不知道的
Squidward, if I didn't know better
还以为那真的是飞船呢
I'd be thinking that was a real alien spaceship
不过我们可知道了  对吧章鱼哥
But we do know better, huh, Squidward?
我错了  行不
I was wrong, okay?
真的有外星人
Aliens are real
我本来在他们飞船上
I was on their ship
跟他们讲我妈的事
and I was telling them about my mother
还有
and--
我们都懂  章鱼哥
We get it, Squidward
根本没有外星人
Aliens don't exist
可真的有外星人
But they do exist
果然
Of course